[
    {
        "question": "Who was sworn in as Uruguay's President?",
        "options": [
            "Luis Lacalle Pou",
            "Yamand\u00fa Orsi",
            "Jos\u00e9 Mujica",
            "Tabar\u00e9 V\u00e1zquez",
            "Luis Alberto Heber"
        ],
        "answer": "Yamand\u00fa Orsi",
        "source": "<a href=\"t.me/PRIYATIWARIGA\">source</a>"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the main objective behind the RBI\u2019s decision to roll back its 2023 increase in risk weights on bank loans to NBFCs, effective April 1, 2025?",
        "options": [
            "To increase bank credit growth",
            "To release bank capital and enhance NBFC lending",
            "To reduce microloan risk weights",
            "To regulate non-banking financial institutions more strictly",
            "To promote foreign loans to NBFCs"
        ],
        "answer": "To release bank capital and enhance NBFC lending",
        "source": "<a href=\"t.me/PRIYATIWARIGA\">source</a>"
    },
    {
        "question": "What was the percentage increase in the All India House Price Index in Q3FY25 compared to the previous year?",
        "options": [
            "2.5%",
            "4.0%",
            "5.2%",
            "1.8%",
            "3.1%"
        ],
        "answer": "3.1%",
        "source": "<a href=\"t.me/PRIYATIWARIGA\">source</a>"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is CRISIL's projected GDP growth rate for FY26?",
        "options": [
            "5.0%",
            "6.0%",
            "6.5%",
            "7.0%",
            "7.5%"
        ],
        "answer": "6.5%",
        "source": "<a href=\"t.me/PRIYATIWARIGA\">source</a>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which two public sector companies have been awarded Navratna status by the central government?",
        "options": [
            "IOC and BP",
            "IRCTC and IRFC",
            "SAIL and Hindustan Zinc",
            "NTPC and ONGC",
            "Power Grid Corporation and GAIL India"
        ],
        "answer": "IRCTC and IRFC",
        "source": "<a href=\"t.me/PRIYATIWARIGA\">source</a>"
    },
    {
        "question": "What significant action did President Donald Trump take regarding the official language of the U.S.?",
        "options": [
            "Made Spanish the official language",
            "Proposed multiple official languages",
            "Announced no official language",
            "Made English the official language",
            "Made French the official language"
        ],
        "answer": "Made English the official language",
        "source": "<a href=\"t.me/PRIYATIWARIGA\">source</a>"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the purpose of the MoU signed by GRSE with the Army?",
        "options": [
            "Build a new army base",
            "Enhance border security",
            "Develop a Modular Steel Bridge",
            "Construct a railway line",
            "Establish a naval base"
        ],
        "answer": "Develop a Modular Steel Bridge",
        "source": "<a href=\"t.me/PRIYATIWARIGA\">source</a>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where was India\u2019s first World Peace Center inaugurated?",
        "options": [
            "New Delhi",
            "Mumbai",
            "Bangalore",
            "Pune",
            "Gurugram"
        ],
        "answer": "Gurugram",
        "source": "<a href=\"t.me/PRIYATIWARIGA\">source</a>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is the Khelo India Winter Games 2025 set to be held?",
        "options": [
            "Shimla",
            "Manali",
            "Gulmarg",
            "Leh",
            "Nainital"
        ],
        "answer": "Gulmarg",
        "source": "<a href=\"t.me/PRIYATIWARIGA\">source</a>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who became the seventh Indian cricketer to play 300 ODIs?",
        "options": [
            "Sachin Tendulkar",
            "MS Dhoni",
            "Virat Kohli",
            "Sourav Ganguly",
            "Rahul Dravid"
        ],
        "answer": "Virat Kohli",
        "source": "<a href=\"t.me/PRIYATIWARIGA\">source</a>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has been roped in by Levi\u2019s as their global ambassador?",
        "options": [
            "Ranveer Singh",
            "Diljit Dosanjh",
            "Virat Kohli",
            "Shah Rukh Khan",
            "Hrithik Roshan"
        ],
        "answer": "Diljit Dosanjh",
        "source": "<a href=\"t.me/PRIYATIWARIGA\">source</a>"
    },
    {
        "question": "What was SEBI's total income in 2023-24 after a 48% rise?",
        "options": [
            "\u20b91,500 Crore",
            "\u20b91,800 Crore",
            "\u20b92,075 Crore",
            "\u20b92,500 Crore",
            "\u20b93,000 Crore"
        ],
        "answer": "\u20b92,075 Crore",
        "source": "<a href=\"t.me/PRIYATIWARIGA\">source</a>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which bank has partnered with Paytm to expand digital payment solutions?",
        "options": [
            "HDFC Bank",
            "ICICI Bank",
            "SBI",
            "RBL Bank",
            "Axis Bank"
        ],
        "answer": "RBL Bank",
        "source": "<a href=\"t.me/PRIYATIWARIGA\">source</a>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is the Exercise Sea Dragon 2025 taking place?",
        "options": [
            "Hawaii",
            "Andaman & Nicobar",
            "Guam",
            "Australia",
            "Japan"
        ],
        "answer": "Guam",
        "source": "<a href=\"t.me/PRIYATIWARIGA\">source</a>"
    },
    {
        "question": "India has emerged as the ______ largest global wealth hub.",
        "options": [
            "1st",
            "2nd",
            "3rd",
            "4th",
            "5th"
        ],
        "answer": "4th",
        "source": "<a href=\"t.me/PRIYATIWARIGA\">source</a>"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Union Cabinet approved a ropeway project from Sonprayag to which holy site?",
        "options": [
            "Badrinath",
            "Kedarnath",
            "Vaishno Devi",
            "Amarnath",
            "Haridwar"
        ],
        "answer": "Kedarnath",
        "source": "<a href=\"t.me/PRIYATIWARIGA\">source</a>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which award was conferred upon PM Modi by Barbados?",
        "options": [
            "Bharat Ratna",
            "Honorary Order of Freedom",
            "Global Peace Award",
            "Order of Excellence",
            "International Leadership Award"
        ],
        "answer": "Honorary Order of Freedom",
        "source": "<a href=\"t.me/PRIYATIWARIGA\">source</a>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who received the Lifetime Achievement Award for Hospitality and Education?",
        "options": [
            "Ratan Tata",
            "Narayana Murthy",
            "Suborno Bose",
            "Anand Mahindra",
            "Mukesh Ambani"
        ],
        "answer": "Suborno Bose",
        "source": "<a href=\"t.me/PRIYATIWARIGA\">source</a>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which Australian cricketer recently retired from ODI cricket?",
        "options": [
            "David Warner",
            "Steve Smith",
            "Pat Cummins",
            "Glenn Maxwell",
            "Marnus Labuschagne"
        ],
        "answer": "Steve Smith",
        "source": "<a href=\"t.me/PRIYATIWARIGA\">source</a>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Sharath Kamal is associated with which sport?",
        "options": [
            "Badminton",
            "Tennis",
            "Table Tennis",
            "Squash",
            "Cricket"
        ],
        "answer": "Table Tennis",
        "source": "<a href=\"t.me/PRIYATIWARIGA\">source</a>"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the primary purpose of SEBI in India?",
        "options": [
            "Regulating banking sector",
            "Managing foreign trade",
            "Overseeing the stock market",
            "Controlling inflation",
            "Issuing currency"
        ],
        "answer": "Overseeing the stock market",
        "source": "<a href=\"t.me/PRIYATIWARIGA\">source</a>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which financial institution has the RBI decided to inject additional liquidity through Open Market Operations (OMO) and a $10B forex swap?",
        "options": [
            "ICICI Bank",
            "HDFC Bank",
            "SBI",
            "Axis Bank",
            "Central Bank"
        ],
        "answer": "Central Bank",
        "source": "<a href=\"t.me/PRIYATIWARIGA\">source</a>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which company bought out SBI's stake in the payments bank joint venture?",
        "options": [
            "Paytm",
            "Jio Financial",
            "PhonePe",
            "Google Pay",
            "Amazon Pay"
        ],
        "answer": "Jio Financial",
        "source": "<a href=\"t.me/PRIYATIWARIGA\">source</a>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where did the technical teams from India and Bangladesh meet ahead of the Ganga Water Treaty renewal talks?",
        "options": [
            "Delhi",
            "Mumbai",
            "Kolkata",
            "Dhaka",
            "Jaipur"
        ],
        "answer": "Kolkata",
        "source": "<a href=\"t.me/PRIYATIWARIGA\">source</a>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Why was NASA's launch of the newest space telescope delayed?",
        "options": [
            "Technical issues",
            "Budget issues",
            "Safety concerns",
            "Weather conditions",
            "Launch pad issue"
        ],
        "answer": "Weather conditions",
        "source": "<a href=\"t.me/PRIYATIWARIGA\">source</a>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which state in India has new habitats identified for expanding the Cheetah reintroduction program?",
        "options": [
            "Uttar Pradesh",
            "Gujarat and Madhya Pradesh",
            "Rajasthan",
            "Karnataka",
            "Maharashtra"
        ],
        "answer": "Gujarat and Madhya Pradesh",
        "source": "<a href=\"t.me/PRIYATIWARIGA\">source</a>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which countries signed a landmark MoU with India to strengthen cooperation in the water, sanitation, and hygiene sector?",
        "options": [
            "Bangladesh",
            "Nepal",
            "Sri Lanka",
            "Bhutan",
            "Afghanistan"
        ],
        "answer": "Nepal",
        "source": "<a href=\"t.me/PRIYATIWARIGA\">source</a>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where did Prime Minister Narendra Modi inaugurate \u2018Vantara\u2019 and feed lion cubs and giraffes?",
        "options": [
            "Ahmedabad",
            "Jamnagar",
            "Surat",
            "Gandhinagar",
            "Bhopal"
        ],
        "answer": "Jamnagar",
        "source": "<a href=\"t.me/PRIYATIWARIGA\">source</a>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which countries have been banned by FIFA from the 2026 World Cup?",
        "options": [
            "Pakistan, Russia, Congo",
            "Pakistan, Iran, North Korea",
            "Russia, Iran, Cuba",
            "Iran, Cuba, Syria",
            "Argentina, Russia, Pakistan"
        ],
        "answer": "Pakistan, Russia, Congo",
        "source": "<a href=\"t.me/PRIYATIWARIGA\">source</a>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which Union Minister announced the Khelo India Para Games 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Amit Shah",
            "Narendra Modi",
            "Dr. Mansukh Mandaviya",
            "Kiren Rijiju",
            "Smriti Irani"
        ],
        "answer": "Dr. Mansukh Mandaviya",
        "source": "<a href=\"t.me/PRIYATIWARIGA\">source</a>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has been appointed as the first-ever woman Union Law Secretary?",
        "options": [
            "Anju Rathi Rana",
            "Nirmala Sitharaman",
            "Smriti Irani",
            "Priya Malik",
            "Rina Kapoor"
        ],
        "answer": "Anju Rathi Rana",
        "source": "<a href=\"t.me/PRIYATIWARIGA\">source</a>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which organization has HDFC Bank signed an MoU with?",
        "options": [
            "Indian Army",
            "Indian Air Force",
            "Indian Navy",
            "DRDO",
            "BSF"
        ],
        "answer": "Indian Air Force",
        "source": "<a href=\"t.me/PRIYATIWARIGA\">source</a>"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the purpose of the partnership between SIDBI and Federal Bank?",
        "options": [
            "MSME Financing",
            "Agriculture Financing",
            "Student Loan Program",
            "Housing Loan Initiative",
            "Education Scheme"
        ],
        "answer": "MSME Financing",
        "source": "<a href=\"t.me/PRIYATIWARIGA\">source</a>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has Federal Bank appointed as its brand ambassador?",
        "options": [
            "Priyanka Chopra",
            "Deepika Padukone",
            "Vidya Balan",
            "Alia Bhatt",
            "Kangana Ranaut"
        ],
        "answer": "Vidya Balan",
        "source": "<a href=\"t.me/PRIYATIWARIGA\">source</a>"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Karnataka government has decided to rename Bengaluru City University in honor of whom?",
        "options": [
            "Jawaharlal Nehru",
            "Manmohan Singh",
            "Rajiv Gandhi",
            "Indira Gandhi",
            "Atal Bihari Vajpayee"
        ],
        "answer": "Manmohan Singh",
        "source": "<a href=\"t.me/PRIYATIWARIGA\">source</a>"
    },
    {
        "question": "India has won which tournament for the third time?",
        "options": [
            "ICC World Cup",
            "ICC Champions Trophy",
            "ICC T20 World Cup",
            "Asia Cup",
            "ICC Test Championship"
        ],
        "answer": "ICC Champions Trophy",
        "source": "<a href=\"t.me/PRIYATIWARIGA\">source</a>"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Delhi Cabinet has approved what monthly aid amount for women?",
        "options": [
            "\u20b91,500",
            "\u20b92,000",
            "\u20b92,500",
            "\u20b93,000",
            "\u20b95,000"
        ],
        "answer": "\u20b92,500",
        "source": "<a href=\"t.me/PRIYATIWARIGA\">source</a>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Madhav National Park has been declared as what?",
        "options": [
            "India's 58th National Park",
            "India's 58th Tiger Reserve",
            "India's First Tiger Reserve",
            "India's First National Park",
            "India's Largest Tiger Reserve"
        ],
        "answer": "India's 58th Tiger Reserve",
        "source": "<a href=\"t.me/PRIYATIWARIGA\">source</a>"
    },
    {
        "question": "India's Astra MkIII 'Gandiva' BVR missile is currently in inflight trials on which aircraft?",
        "options": [
            "Rafale",
            "Mirage 2000",
            "Tejas",
            "Su-30 MKI",
            "F-16"
        ],
        "answer": "Su-30 MKI",
        "source": "<a href=\"t.me/PRIYATIWARIGA\">source</a>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Under which initiative has HDFC Bank launched Project HAKK?",
        "options": [
            "Digital Banking",
            "Green Banking",
            "MSME Financing",
            "Women Empowerment",
            "Air Force Support"
        ],
        "answer": "Air Force Support",
        "source": "<a href=\"t.me/PRIYATIWARIGA\">source</a>"
    },
    {
        "question": "What feature has Paytm UPI introduced for stock trading?",
        "options": [
            "Instant Payment Processing",
            "Fund Blocking for Stock Trading",
            "Direct Bank Transfers",
            "Cash Withdrawal Services",
            "Loan Assistance"
        ],
        "answer": "Fund Blocking for Stock Trading",
        "source": "<a href=\"t.me/PRIYATIWARIGA\">source</a>"
    }
]